Guide to the Senior Honor Essays of Yale Students
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Senior honor essays of Yale students
1889-1979
RU 118
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
35.5
(86 boxes)
The materials consist of a selected collection of essays written by Yale seniors to meet graduation requirements in various departments.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 47 (YRG 47), Collections documenting teaching and learning in Yale academic programs.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged in two series: I. Alphabetical. II. Numerical.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of a selected collection of essays written by Yale seniors to meet graduation requirements in various departments.
Essays; Yale University -- Students
- Alphabetical, Series I
  - Anwar, Pasha S.--On the Specification of a Maoist Praxis, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Amento, Carl Joseph--Patterns of Oligopolistic Behavior in the Venezuelan Political System, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Alter, John C.--This Side Idolatry, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Allen, George H.--The Political Theory of L. T. Hobhouse, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Peter A.--The Bildungsroman in English, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Albom, James--Throw Down the Spears, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Kenneth L.--Chaucer's Canterbury Tales: an Overview, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Alegi, Peter C.--A History of Catholicism at Yale to 1943, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Axthelm, Peter M.--The Modern Confessional Novel, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Bellamy, Rufus T.--The Development of T.S. Eliot's Sensibility as a Christian Writer, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Beal, Arthur A.--Mormonism and the Nation, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Barnes, Peter--Alfred E. Smith's Candidacy and the Campaign of 1928 in New Mexico, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Barnes, Jim--A Study of Ishmael, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Bain, Richard C.--The Co-operative Commonwealth Federation-- Canada's Socialist Party, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Baginski, Frank C.--Design of a Pilot Plant for the Recovery of Copper, Chromium, and Zinc from Oxide Sludges Made from Brass Mill Pickle Liquors and Wash Waters 2 copies, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Barker, Patrick C.--Towards an Ambigious Equilibrium: A Study in Comedy and Tragedy, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Britton, Coburn H.--Two Early Renaissance Biographies: A Critical Study, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Brossell, Gordon--The Philosophic Mind: A Valuation of Wordsworth's Excursion, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Bristol, Michael D.--Miltonic Forms and Myths in Blake's Milton, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Bradley, Larry--Secularization in the Novels and Short Stories of Nathaniel Hawthorne, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Braun, Saul M.--Full of Secret Whispers, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Brink, Folger--Seven Plays of Christopher Fry, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Blanc, Roger D.--The Narrative Perspective: An Interpretive Reading of Chaucer's Troilus and Criseyde, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Bernard, Jules--The Vision of Innocence: A Study of Tennyson's Major Symbolism, 1833-1842, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Boddie, A. W.--The Ironic Imagination of Wallace Stevens, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Boles, Alan--Conrad's Use of Verbal Exchanges in His Autobiographies and Short Tales, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Bernheimer, Alan--Liquid Steel, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Baker, James Marshall--Gerard Manley Hopkins--a Commentary on His Early Works, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Brill, Steven D.--Policy Change and Political Outcomes in a Democracy, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Boly, John R.--The Development of Wallace Steven's Aesthetic, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Burrows, Calvin--The Mountain of Truth, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Browne, Richard J.--Art and Nature in Goethe's Children, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Burrows, George S.--The Builders of Chicago, undated (Box 5)
  - Brown, J. Crosby--A Comparative Evaluation of Seven Modern Verse-Translations of Beowulf, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Biltekoff, James Robert--The Black Revolutionary Theater, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Csar, Michael--Ideology, Dissent, and the Press, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Capron, Paul III--Three Great Utopias, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Coombs, Orde M.--The Posture of Alienation in the Works of James Baldwin, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Cowan, Dennis K.,--The Genesis of the Indian New Deal, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Carlson,--A Look at Wallace Steven's Poetics and Their Background, undated (Box 6)
  - Carey, William B.--The New Haven Symphony Orchestra, 1950 (Box 6)
  - Carroll, Christopher F.--History and Vision in Chaucer's Troilus, 1958 (Box 6)
  - Calderón, Ricardo A.--Seventeenth-Century Christian Humanist: A Study of Milton's Early Period, 1600-1640, undated (Box 6)
  - Carter, Robert A.--The Development of "Psychological Tragedy" in Three Plays of Ibsen, 1958 (Box 6)
  - Cheney, Donald S.--Vision and Revision: Nathaniel Hawthorne and Our Old Home, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Chen, Victor--Love and Art--F. Scott Fitzgerald, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Clapp, Roger S.--The Creation Tradition and Milton, 1962 (Box 7)
  - Chasin, Richard M.--The Derivation and Application of a Theory of Self-Estrangement Suggested by Marx's Concept of Alienated Labor, 1956 (Box 7)
  - Chodikoff, Norman--The Shape of the Sibyl, 1958 (Box 7)
  - Conant, Jonathan B.--King Horn: A Critical Study, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Cook, Herbert S., Jr.--The Hero as Moral Eunuch: Fitzgerald, Dos Passos, and the New Jewish Novel, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Cossman, David--Hart Crane's White Buildings, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Cates, Willard--Harry Weinberger: A Civil Libertarian and His Times 1915-1942, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Cribley, Bruce R.--Mind, Imagination, and World in Wordsworth's Poetry, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Crowley, P. E.--The Constitutional Development of Ceylon 1920-1940, 1941 (Box 8)
  - Copeland, J. R., Jr.--Poems and Stories, undated (Box 8)
  - Durchslag, James Howard--Diploma Days, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Dexter, Donn--The Bay of Tonkin Resolution, 1972 (Box 9)
  - DeVoe, George M.--Samuel Johnson's Poetry, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Deck, Raymond H.--Signal of the Morning, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Davis, C. Roger--The Wrecks of Eden, 1965 (Box 9)
  - Dibbell, Adam W.--Notes Towards the Definition of the Modern Short Story, 1961 (Box 9)
  - Dahl, Steven R.--F. Scott Fitzgerald: the Development of Early Themes and Their Relevance to the Uniqueness of The Great Gatsby, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Davis, Burt L. III--The Short and Not So Happy Life of Kearneyism in California, 1964 (Box 9)
  - Davies, John B.--An Approach to James Agee, 1962 (Box 9)
  - Evans, Dennis--Poems, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Eberle, William--The Catholic Vision, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Engelman, Robert J.--The Shorter Poems of Herman Melville--A Critical Exegesis, 1954 (Box 10)
  - Erikson, Donald A.--The Plays of John Webster, 1953 (Box 10)
  - Everett, E. H.--Twenty Poems by Bertolt Brecht, translated, 1958 (Box 10)
  - Erikson, K. William--J.R.R. Tolkien: A Critical Approach to His Novels, 1966 (Box 10)
  - Estroff, Harry L.--Sufficient to Have Stood--A Value Study in Modern Literature, 1965 (Box 10)
  - Franklin, Robert M.--Eugene O'Neill: the Religious Plays of the Twenties, 1965 (Box 11)
  - Frede, Richard--Four Stories, undated (Box 11)
  - Fox, Denton-- Arabia Deserta and Seven Pillars of Wisdom, 1951 (Box 11)
  - Festersen, Paul F.--Satire in the Novels of Aldous Huxley, 1961 (Box 11)
  - Fichter, Andrew J.--Ideas of Order in Shakespeare's Late Plays, 1967 (Box 11)
  - Farr, George F., Jr.--The Novels of E. M. Forster, 1958 (Box 11)
  - Firth, Thomas V.--The Flower and the Weed--A Study of Shakespeare's Sonnets, 1961 (Box 11)
  - Fennel, Justus J., Jr.--Jonathan Swift's View of the Nature of Man, undated (Box 11)
  - Fullerton, Gregory L.--Representation and Reapportionment, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Fersch, Ellsworth--John Webster, 1957 (Box 12)
  - Free, William--Walpole on Shakespeare, undated (Box 12)
  - Frey, Charles--Pastoral in The Winter's Tale, 1957 (Box 12)
  - Fuller, Henry M.--Miracles and the Miraculous in English Thought, 1935 (Box 12)
  - Forer, Edward L.--A Survey of Department Stores and Their Problems, 1940 (Box 12)
  - Gorelik, Gregory M.--Tea, 1969 (Box 13)
  - Collin, James--The Problem of Ezra Pound, 1953 (Box 13)
  - Graham, Donald A.--Mind Has Mountains--Some Poems of Gerard Manley Hopkins, 1963 (Box 13)
  - Gross, Peter A.--The Postwar Comic World in England, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Greer, David C.--Patterns of Unity in The Temple, 1959 (Box 13)
  - Griffin, John D.--The Dream as Tragic Symbol, 1962 (Box 13)
  - Gleysteen, Culver--An Enlightened History Book by Chin Ching-Ch'iu, Translated and Annotated, 1944 (Box 13)
  - Grab, Frederic D.--Ezra Pound and the Greek Tradition, 1956 (Box 13)
  - Getzen, Thomas E.--The Shandean Affirmation, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Glickman, James A.--We Are All Once Upon a Time, 1970 (Box 14)
  - Gams, Nathan--Elizabethan Pageantry and Versions of Elizabeth in The Faerie Queene, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Golson, G. Barry--Another, Better Spring, 1967 (Box 14)
  - Garabedian, J. A.--Williams Country--The Fictional World of Tennessee Williams, 1965 (Box 14)
  - Goldstein, Thomas J.--The Golden Cane of Kingship: Studies in Political Power in Shakespeare, 1967 (Box 14)
  - Gill, John H.--The Shield of Achilles in George Chapman's Illiad, undated (Box 14)
  - Gersch, Miles M.--A City in Recollection: William Carlos William's Paterson, 1965 (Box 14)
  - Gould, G. K., Jr.--The Thematic Pattern in Shakespeare's Early Romantic Comedies, 1952 (Box 14)
  - Hoffman, Peter--Indian Fishing Rights in Washington--the Puyallup-Nisqually Experience, 1971 (Box 15)
  - Henneman, Edward O.--The Escape from Fantasy, 1959 (Box 15)
  - Heyman, Philip J.--"Stupend Metamorphoses" 2 copies, 1960 (Box 15)
  - Hedgcock, Marc--The Piety of Order: Wallace Stevens' Harmonium, undated (Box 15)
  - Hulteen, Irving R.--Three Major Concerns in Shelley's Poetry, undated (Box 15)
  - Harned, David B.--The Foreign, 1954 (Box 15)
  - Hamann, Charles M.--Unity, Order, and Nature in Thomson's Seasons, 1961 (Box 15)
  - Hagerty, Sheward--Earth and Water
  - Hopkins, J. Wallace, Jr.--Seeds of Time, 1953 (Box 16)
  - Hogan-Shaidali, S.A.E.--In Unfit Proportion to the Universal Occasion, undated (Box 16)
  - Hopkins, Benjamin T.--Camila, 1954 (Box 16)
  - Hemingson, Richard H.--The Structure of The Prelude, 1960 (Box 16)
  - Holt, Clyde F.--The Miraculous Verb, 1962 (Box 16)
  - Hoey, Laurence--Point of View in Three Novels of Jane Austen, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Holleb, Alan--The Technique of Hemingway's Short Stories, 1967 (Box 16)
  - Hill, George S., Jr.--The Range of Mark Twain's Satire, undated (Box 16)
  - Haupt, Garry E.--Sir Fulke Greville: Poet and Thinker, 1955 (Box 17)
  - Hunter, John W., Jr.--Gertrude Stein, 1954 (Box 17)
  - Hurley, Douglas L.--The Tragic Novels of Thomas Hardy--Three Studies, 1966 (Box 17)
  - Houlahan, Michael C.--The Poetry of A. E. Housman, 1962 (Box 17)
  - Hufstader, Jonathan--The Flaming Mirror 2 copies, 1960 (Box 17)
  - Howe, Con Edward--Study in Decentralization of Urban Government: Model Cities in New York, 1972 (Box 18)
  - Hengen, Richard L.--The Ironic Vision of W. B. Yeats, 1969 (Box 18)
  - Hogan, Anthony--The Bold Northwest Men, undated (Box 18)
  - Hutt, Peter B.--Dairy Cooperatives in the United States, 1956 (Box 18)
  - Israel, J. L., Jr.--James Joyce's Ulysses: A Critical Study, 1954 (Box 19)
  - Johnson, Thomas R.--Heroism and the Public Order: Tragic Structure in Jacobean Tragedy, 1969 (Box 20)
  - Jackson, Sheila R.--Black Political Power in the Deep South, 1972 (Box 20)
  - Johnston, William--Night Season, 1967 (Box 20)
  - Johnston, Thomas M.C., Jr.--The Poetry of Archibald MacLeish, 1959 (Box 20)
  - Judd, H. Stanley--The Merrythought, undated (Box 20)
  - Knott, J. D.--The Artist as Confidence Man, 1966 (Box 21)
  - Knott, John R., Jr.--William Faulkner: the Heart's Truth, 1959 (Box 21)
  - Kirshbaum, Howard M.--The Rhythms of E.M. Forster, 1960 (Box 21)
  - Knudson, Peder H.--The Occupation of San Juan Island, undated (Box 21)
  - Kany, Steven C.--Forms and Themes in the Contemporary Novel, 1966 (Box 21)
  - Kilbourne, Frederick W.--On the Expediency of the Proposed Income Tax, 1894 (Box 21)
  - Kiang, Stuart C.H.--A Structural Analysis of the Late Poetry and Poetics of Wallace Stevens, 1966 (Box 21)
  - Kass, Stephen--Wrestle the Great Ear, 1961 (Box 21)
  - Kossan, Richard E.--The Individual's Land: An Approach to Faulkner's Yoknapatawpha World 2 copies, 1964 (Box 22)
  - Kornblum, Peter E.--The Womanly Defense--Heroines in the Drama of Shakespeare, Webster, and Ford, 1966 (Box 22)
  - Kohlmann, William--Young England: An Ideology, 1945 (Box 22)
  - Koskoff, David E.--A Study of the Gachupin War of 1812-1813, 1961 (Box 22)
  - Levett, David R.--The Honor of Warriors and Lovers--a Thematic Study of Five of Shakespeare's Mature Plays, undated (Box 23)
  - Lewis, Edmund H.--Lord Cochrane: His Aid in Freeing Chile and Peru from Spanish Rule, 1907 (Box 23)
  - Leighton, William B.--Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium Data for Systems Involved in the Esterification of Ethyl Acetate, 1936 (Box 23)
  - Lee, John--Three Stories, 1954 (Box 23)
  - Leicester, H.M., Jr.--The Mirror of the Mind--A Reading of Chaucer's Troilus and Criseyde, 1963 (Box 23)
  - Lauppé, Carl III--An Approach to King Lear, 1966 (Box 23)
  - Laun, Louis F., Jr.--Public Policy toward Chain Stores with Special Reference to Grocery and Grocery and Meat Chains, 1942 (Box 23)
  - Levy, Mark Eliot--Robert Frost: the Poet as Philosopher of Limits, 1970 (Box 24)
  - Langbein, Stanley I.--Great World and Small: Sterne's Tristam Shandy, 1970 (Box 24)
  - Lieberman, Steven M.--The Failure of Reform in Northern Ireland, 1972 (Box 24)
  - Lyons, Robert P.--The Political Police of Soviet Russia, 1948 (Box 24)
  - Lohmann, John--Elihu Yale's Art Collection, undated (Box 24)
  - Louis, Marshall R., Jr.--The Innocent Scourge--the Prophet and the World in Flannery O'Conner, 1965 (Box 24)
  - Lord, Charles E., II--John Dryden and the Custom of Literary Patronage during the Restoration, 1949 (Box 24)
  - Leete, Harmon--William Shakespeare--An Attempt to Define His Concept of Honor in Relation to the Prevailing Schools of Thought of Western Europe, 1953 (Box 24)
  - Malugen, John C.--The Alexandrians of Lawrence Durrell, 1965 (Box 25)
  - Mark, Lawrence H., Jr.--Young from the Quiet Land, 1955 (Box 25)
  - Margolin, Richard--Six Stories, undated (Box 25)
  - McDermott, Joseph P.--The Collected Stories of William Faulkner and An Aristocracy of Action, undated (Box 25)
  - MacKinnon, William P.--President Buchanan and the Utah Expedition, a Question of Expediency rather than Principle, 1960 (Box 25)
  - McCausland, Thomas G.--Passage to Peace, 1949 (Box 25)
  - McIntosh, James L.--The Hero in Shaw's Drama, 1966 (Box 25)
  - McDonald, Julius F.--The Know-Nothing Party in the Border States, 1998 (Box 25)
  - Moore, Thurston M.--Shadowy Tribes of Mind, 1954 (Box 26)
  - Monette, Paul L.--The Hero of In Memoriam, 1967 (Box 26)
  - Moncreiff, Robert--The Early Career of Ezra Pound, 1952 (Box 26)
  - Martin, David C.--The Mind of F. Scott Fitzgerald, 1965 (Box 26)
  - Maurin, Gaston C.--On Shelley and Eliot 2 copies, 1961 (Box 26)
  - Marshall, Pardee--The Disputed Boundaries of Maine, undated (Box 26)
  - Meisel, Perry--Thomas Hardy: Consciousness and Community, 1970 (Box 26)
  - Martin, David B.H.-- Henry VIII and The Two Noble Kinsmen, 1969 (Box 27)
  - Miller, David A.--The Grace of Intensity, 1970 (Box 27)
  - Miller, Stephen--Bronze Desert: A Story of the Panda, 1970 (Box 27)
  - Macomber, S. Kingsley--The Mask of Melancholy, 1965 (Box 27)
  - Milch, D.--The Groundlings, 1966 (Box 27)
  - Newman, Scott--Dickens as a Symbolic Novelist, 1969 (Box 28)
  - Nesseler, Lonnie J.--Structure and the Integral Being: Studies in the Novel, undated (Box 28)
  - Nierintz, William E.--"California or Bust" The Overland Journal of N. L. Weed, 1849-1850 2 copies, 1961 (Box 28)
  - Oram, Bill--Total Vision: the Development of Blake's Myth, 1791-1794, undated (Box 29)
  - Odoner, Ellen J.--Constitution-Making for Men and Natural Resources in Montana, 1884 and 1889, 1973 (Box 29)
  - Ostergren, Christopher--Brecht and Arden: the Dramaturgy of Contradiction, undated (Box 29)
  - Oakes, Tom--The Relation of Christianity to Poetic Form in Three Nineteenth Century Poems of Religious Vision, 1956 (Box 29)
  - O'Brien, Bruce--Marianne Moore: the Power of the Visible in Poetry, 1953 (Box 29)
  - Parker, Robert F.--Conrad's Major Novels: A Study of Narrative Technique, 1970 (Box 30)
  - Pelton, Robert D.--A Study of T.S. Eliot's The Four Quartets as Poetic Meditations., undated (Box 30)
  - Palm, Carleton R.--The Search for a New Trail, 1959 (Box 30)
  - Price, Jonathan L.--J.D. Salinger: the Development of the Narrator in His Fiction, 1966 (Box 30)
  - Porter, Frank B., Jr.--The Major Odes of John Keats, 1959 (Box 30)
  - Patterson, Lee W.--Lyric Action: A Preliminary Study, 1962 (Box 30)
  - Pattison, Robert--The Realism of Sir Walter Scott, undated (Box 30)
  - Patterson, Day L.--A Portrait of Clive Day, 1966 (Box 30)
  - Post, Herschel--The Double Perspective, 1961 (Box 30)
  - Putzel, Henry III--The Tangible Truth 2 copies, 1964 (Box 31)
  - Pollack, Frederick--The Development of the Narrator in Pre-Romantic Poetry, 1967 (Box 31)
  - Queen, Thomas W.--Congress, the President, and the Power to Commit Armed Force, 1972 (Box 32)
  - Reichbart, Richard H.--Actium, 1964 (Box 33)
  - Reaske, Christopher--The Caged Bird, 1963 (Box 33)
  - Reed, Walter L.--The Poetry of Dylan Thomas: Approaches to Interpretation, 1965 (Box 33)
  - Reid, Robert L.--H.D.'s Later Poems: A Critical Study, 1966 (Box 33)
  - Rogoff, Gordon M.--Sean O'Casey and the Search for Fulfillment, 1952 (Box 33)
  - Reed, Joseph W., Jr.--Christopher Marlow's Tragedy of Dido, Queen of Carthage, 1954 (Box 33)
  - Rapaport, David--The Ethics of Knighthood, 1966 (Box 33)
  - Roth, Merle--"Th' Unwilling Dross": Themes of Materialism in Shelley's Poetry, 1971 (Box 34)
  - Rodriguez, Oswaldo A.--Law, Policy-Making and Human Rights: The U.N. Experience, 1972 (Box 34)
  - Rahtz, Roger A.--The Art of Literary Construction, 1969 (Box 34)
  - Richards, John R.--W.B. Yeats: A Scultured Art, 1962 (Box 34)
  - Roche, Thomas P., Jr.--Nature, Wit, and Emily Dickinson, 1953 (Box 34)
  - Rogers, W.E.--Cross-Correspondence in Paradise Lost, 1966 (Box 34)
  - Robertson, J.B.--Church Architecture, 1926 (Box 34)
  - Rosa, Robert M.--Pastoral in Romance Contents, 1966 (Box 34)
  - Ross, James J.--An Essay on Satire, undated (Box 34)
  - Richards, David A.--"This War of Innuendoes", 1965 (Box 34)
  - Richards, David A.--The Memorable Preservations, 1967 (Box 34)
  - Roe, David B.--A WAKE NING, 1969 (Box 35)
  - Slevin, Joseph R.--Young England: the Biography of a Dream, 1939 (Box 36)
  - Sanderson, Kenneth M.--Plots and Plotters in Shakespeare's Plays, 1958 (Box 36)
  - Schnee, Edward--Chain Stores, 1941 (Box 36)
  - Sharp, William L.--The Convention of the House in 19th Century American Literature, 1961 (Box 36)
  - Selden, Samuel--"While the Horses Are Saddled", 1922 (Box 36)
  - Shapiro, Allan E.--The Social and Political Thought of Jacques Maritain, 1947 (Box 36)
  - Sherman, Stanford--A Study of the Short Stories of Ernest Hemingway, undated (Box 36)
  - Simmons, Fred A.--The Fundamental Conflict between Heart and Herd in Four of Dostoevsky's Characters, 1957 (Box 36)
  - Straw, Lynwood--George Eliot: the Morality of Compassion, 1964 (Box 37)
  - Sharon, William A.--A Century of Carriage Building in New Haven, 1942 (Box 37)
  - Stanton, D.L.--The Theme of Power: A Study in the Modern Political Novel, 1953 (Box 37)
  - Stott, William--One Year's Writing, 1962 (Box 37)
  - Stommel, Henry M.--The Astronomy of the Old Testament, 1942 (Box 37)
  - Stommel, Henry M.--John Kepler and His Philosophy, undated (Box 37)
  - Sperry, Mark--Jonathan Swift--A Study in Idea and Expression, 1961 (Box 37)
  - Schweitzer, John C.--The Literary Use of Environment in Three Novels, undated (Box 37)
  - Stambler, Peter L.--The Country Marriages, 1966 (Box 37)
  - Schick, Robert--The Origin of the Oregon Mission of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions: A Case Study in Cultural Misunderstanding, 1974 (Box 38)
  - Schramm, Lenn--The Apotheosis of Solitude--The Textes pour Rein of Samuel Beckett, 1971 (Box 38)
  - Stanley, Harold W.--Referents for Legislative Behavior in a One-Party Legislatures: The Case of the 1971 Alabama State Senate, 1972 (Box 38)
  - Sussman, Robert M.--Three American Novelists of Manners: James, Wharton, and Fitzgerald, 1969 (Box 38)
  - Sullivan, Walter S., Jr,--The Conservative Thought of Lord Clarendon, 1940 (Box 38)
  - Shimoda, B. K.--Kagawa and His Kingdom of God Movement, 1940 (Box 38)
  - Sullivan, Paul W.--Fall and Redemption: A Study of Religious Imagery in the Writings of William Faulkner, 1961 (Box 38)
  - Schullenberger, William--The Elements of Power, 1969 (Box 39)
  - Seltzer, Richard W.--Dryden's Exemplary Drama, 1969 (Box 39)
  - Sattler, Rosanna--An Analysis of "Democrats '66" and Its Influence within the Framework of the Contemporary Dutch Political System, 1972 (Box 39)
  - Salfras, Stanley E.--T. S. Eliot's Four Quartets, 1970 (Box 39)
  - Trower, C. Christopher--Faulkner: Freedom and Slavery, 1970 (Box 40)
  - Toy, David E--Hudibras: A Study in Hypocrisy, 1953 (Box 40)
  - Turnage, William A.--The Impeachment of Warren Hastings, 1965 (Box 40)
  - Tubesing, Richard L.--The Voice of the Prophet: A Definitive Study of The Marriage of Heaven and Hell, undated (Box 40)
  - Thanhouser, Lloyd F.--Trash, 1922 (Box 40)
  - Thomas, Jeffrey F.--The Chrome-Plated Jungle: A Study of the Satirical World of Evelyn Waugh, 1960 (Box 40)
  - Teare, Donald A.--The New Yorker Profile, 1953 (Box 40)
  - Taft, William A.--Thacheray's Plots and Heroines, 1966 (Box 40)
  - Venit, James--The Vision of Franz Kafka, undated (Box 41)
  - Van Dyke, Jon M.--The Imagination of Yeats, 1964 (Box 41)
  - Westbrook, Robert B.--The Quest for Security and the Dream of Empire: The Role of the West in American Development, 1754-1804, 1972 (Box 42)
  - Walker, Gordon--Positions on and of Death in T.S. Eliot's Four Quartets, 1966 (Box 42)
  - Wagoner, Walter D.--Philosophy of Richard Oastler--A Christian Tory, 1941 (Box 42)
  - Wilson, Neil C.--Descriptive Studies of San Francisco, 1912 (Box 42)
  - Webb, E. Jackson--Four Short Stories, 1958 (Box 42)
  - Weil, Roger A.--Women in Faulkner, 1964 (Box 42)
  - Willoughby, J. W.--W.H. Auden's Theory of Light Verse, 1952 (Box 42)
  - Weimar, Michael--The Theatre of Restraint, 1967 (Box 42)
  - Willoughby, J. W.--Half a Cup of Life's Liquor, 1952 (Box 42)
  - Wolcher, Wayne D.--The Difficulty of Justice, undated (Box 43)
  - Williams, William II--W. B. Yeats--The Anatomy of a Myth, 1962 (Box 43)
  - Wilcox, Jarvis--The Attribution of the Circumcision of Christ, 1964 (Box 43)
  - Wilcox, William P.--Two Short Stories and a Novel in Progress, 1956 (Box 43)
  - Wolf, Thomas--Robert Browning's Growth to Poetic Maturity, 1960 (Box 43)
  - Wilson, Kenneth J.--The Poetry of Order--a Study of Book VI of The Faerie Queen, 1966 (Box 43)
  - Wood, Norton E.--Washington Correspondent 1840-1841--The Letters of William Cowper Wood, 1941 (Box 43)
  - Watson, David G.--Border States -- poems, 1970 (Box 44)
  - Wheelwright, H. J., Jr.--The Development of the Individual and Society in Restoration and Early 18th Century Tragedy and Comedy, 1969 (Box 44)
  - Wynn, Douglas C.--Strike for the Laws, undated (Box 44)
  - White, Edgar J.--The Sun and the Wind, 1968 (Box 44)
  - Woodson, Thomas--The Hero as Artist: Ulysses and The Magic Mountain, 1953 (Box 44)
  - Wichelms, Miles D.--The Concept of Greatness in Marlowe's Tamburlaine and Doctor Faustus, 1966 (Box 44)
  - Woodside, John M. III--The Artist and "The Riddle of the Painful Earth", 1966 (Box 44)
  - Wang, Peter N.--The Affair with the Gods, 1970 (Box 45)
  - Wright, Dan--Hitchhike, undated (Box 45)
  - Wright, Minturn T., III--The American Dictator: A Study of Huey P. Long, Jr., 1949 (Box 45)
  - Wright, Dan--Four One-Act Plays, 1949 (Box 45)